Guide to the Harold A. Mooney Papers SC1183
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Harold A. Mooney papers
1993-2015
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Mooney, Harold A.
SC1183
20 Linear Feet (14 boxes)
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
Dr. Mooney entered the University of California at Berkley as a political science major, but was forced to halt his studies for economic reasons and accepted a job on a freighter traveling down the west coast of the Americas. While transiting the Panama Canal, he read in a magazine about being a collector for the United States Department of Agriculture's Plant Exploration unit, which lead to a major change in his career path. Dr. Mooney, who had taken a strong interest in plants through his activities in the mountains of California, was extremely attracted to an occupation in which he could both study plants and go on adventurous travels. So he transferred to the University of California's Santa Barbara campus, which had a plant ecology program.
In 1957, he researched the physiological processes of Arctic-Alpine plants over a vast natural range extending from Alaska to the Rocky Mountains. He studied photosynthesis and respiration of the plants using an infrared gas analyzer and equipment that he helped to design and was able to demonstrate the physiological basis for ecotypic differentiation by comparing the plants that were raised in controlled environments with naturally occurring plants. He showed that plants adapted their physiological processes to their local environments.
After he obtained his doctorate in 1960, he embarked on research into convergent evolution that showed that different plant species develop the same physiological characteristics in response to the same severe environments. He earned acclaim for demonstrating that similarities between different species were not limited to form, which had already been demonstrated, but also extended to function. He accomplished this by comparing the ecology and physiological characteristics of plants in the drought-limited Mediterranean climates in the geographically disparate California and Chilean coastal regions and Mediterranean Basin.
In the 1970s, he took a broader approach to examine not only carbon gain but carbon use by plants in an area of California ranging from the desert to the White Mountains and applied a cost-benefit approach to clarify how carbon resources are allocated to different sites in plants for photosynthesis, or various other functions. He had a significant impact on later studies into plant physiological ecology and advanced research into carbon gain and use in plants by showing in a detailed cost analysis how plants obtain carbohydrates and nitrogen, and how they distribute and store them to obtain the greatest effect with the lowest expenditure of energy.
Through these studies, Dr. Mooney showed how plant species and groups of species respond to their environments, thereby contributing to the theoretical framework of plant physiological ecology, and developed research methodologies for assessing how plants interact with their biotic environments. To date he has authored over 400 scientific books, papers and articles.
In the latter half of the 1980s, he pursued research into the effect of the invasion of different plant species on naturally occurring species under the auspices of the Scientific Committee on Problems of the Environment (SCOPE), setting up the first global evaluation of invasive plant species. He regarded the acceleration of problems related to invasive species due to increased international commerce with grave concern, recognized the need for joint research between naturalists and social scientists, and launched the Global Invasive Species Program with many international institutions as partners. Through such programs, he has brought awareness to the topic of the impact of human activities upon ecosystems through species introductions.
Dr. Mooney has played an international leadership role in recent years, especially with problems related to biodiversity and global warming. In addition, he has been active in building up worldwide communities and networks of ecologists and scientists in other disciplines and arranging international conferences on the environment. He played a central role in the International Geosphere-Biosphere Program (IGBP), building up an international organization of scientists and having an influential part in setting the guidelines for the formulation of environmental policies. He has advanced numerous international research programs as Secretary General and Vice-President of the International Council for Science (ICSU). Furthermore, he is working to solicit the interest of the general public in many scientific topics through the media and other channels. As president of the Ecological Society of America he helped launched the publication of a new journal called Ecological Applications that is intended to make use of ecology as a useful tool for management, and worked to promote the designation of the International Biodiversity Observation Year.
Dr. Mooney has demonstrated the importance of ecological studies in the research of changes in the global environment and helped to build the foundation for the field of global ecology. Now universities around the world are establishing global ecology research departments. He continues to work toward the development of new environmental sciences that will be required for the continued existence of humankind.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of correspondence, subject files, research files, committee records, and other materials documenting the impacts of global environmental change on terrestrial ecosystems, especially on ecosystem function, productivity and biodiversity.
Ecology -- Congresses.; Environmental protection -- Congresses.; Environmental policy -- United States.; Mooney, Harold A.; Mooney, Harold A.
- Millennium Ecosystem Assessment
  - Contributor's Memorandum of Agreement MA Synthesis Reports, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Millennium Assessment Report Letter, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ecosystems and Human Well-Being, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Contributor's Agreement, 2003 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter from Larry R. Kohler, 2000 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Revised Ma "Design" and Work plan, 1999 Oct. 25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - International Ecosystem Assessment, 1999 Oct. 22 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Institutions and Governance Strategy, 1999 Dec. 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Project Brief, 1999 Dec. 29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Millennium Assessment Steering Committee Meeting Summary, 1999 Sept.1-Oct. 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Facsimile Steering Committee Meeting Materials, 1999 Aug. 30 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - SCOPE Working Group on Scenario, 1999 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Referee's Report World Resources Institute, 1999 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Advisory Group Invitees - by Country, 1999 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Moralizing Ecosystem Science to Support Human Development, 1999 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Millennium Assessment Steering Committee, 1999 Feb. 24 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Harold A. Mooney Biographical Sketch, 1999 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Draft Proposals for Consideration at Feb. 9 Steering Committee Meeting of the Millennium Assessment, 1999 Jan. 14 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Classic Collection, 1999 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Call B. Moore, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Five Parallel Ecosystem Breakout Groups, 1999 Feb. 11 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Millennium Assessment of the State of the World's Ecosystems (3 copies), 1998 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Millennium Assessment Administration, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2000 March (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2000 July (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2000 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2000 Sept. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2000 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Millennium Ecosystem Assessment Sub-Global Component: Purpose, Structure and Protocols, 2000 Nov. 18 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2000 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Millennium Assessment Workshop, 2000 Nov. 2-3 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2000 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2001 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Conference Calls, 2001 Jan. 16-18 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2001 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Millennium Assessment Meetings, 2001 Feb. 4-6 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2001 March (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Millennium Assessment Meeting Montreal, 2001 March (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Ma Synthesis Mexico City, 2004 June 30-July 2 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - MA-Synthesis, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Synthesis/Draft, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - MA - SDM's, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Ecosystems and their Services, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Memos - Conceptual Framework, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - CF/SP Drafts, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - MA - Conceptual Report Draft 1 Millennium Assessment, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Ecosystems and Human Well-Being Pamphlet, circa 2000 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Co-Chair Meeting, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Methodology Manual, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Payment Current (blank folder), undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Biostores Purchases, 2002 April-July (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Genesys Conferencing Service, 2002 Aug. 23 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - National Academy of Science/Affiliated Science Organizations, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Wed/Thurs Co-Chairs Call, 2002 Oct. 28 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Co-Chair Mtg. Report, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Authors by Country, 2002 Aug. 18 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Names to Walt Reid and Angela Cropper, 2002 Oct. 14 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Authors by Country (2nd copy), 2002 Aug. 18 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - CLAS (empty folder), undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Panel Member Memos, 2002 July (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - MA Tasks and Responsibilities, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Lead Arthur Nominations, 2002 July (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Fellowship Program, circa 2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - MA CF/AP Mtg. Frankfurt, Germany, 2002 Aug. 20-24 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Secretariat Business (Memos/Organizational Meetings), 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General Meetings Schedule-Millennium Assessment, 2002 Aug. 27 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - MA Board, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Background Information - MA, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - MA Core Data Sets Draft 7, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - ESA Meeting, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Media Coverages, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Scenario Working Groups, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Condition Working Groups, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Launching Activities, circa 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Plan de discusion nacional de productos de la Evalucion del Milenio, 20 May 2003 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Outreach & Engagement Group, 28 Aug. 2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - H. Mooney DC Trip Report, 2002 Dec. 3 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Assessment Panel Members & US-Based Working Group Members, 2002 July (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Preliminary Report/Draft, 2002 Sept. 10 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Millennium Ecosystem Assessment, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Teleconferencing, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - DC Trip, 2002 Dec. 7 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Note to Habbiba/ Preliminary Report/Draft, 2002 Sept. 10 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Millennium Assessment Affiliation, 2002 Oct. 25 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Dec. 4 Follow-up on Millennium Assessment, 2002 Oct. 25 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Slate Dept., 2002 Dec. 4 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - U.S. Government Meetings as of Sept. 2, 2002 Sept. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - MEA - USFWS Contacts, 2002 Sept. 15 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Letter to Aristides Patrinos, 2002 July 18 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Assessment Panel Members & US-Based Working Group Members, 2002 July (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - U.S. Government Agency Meetings, 2002 Sept. 9-10 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - U.S. Officials, 2002 July (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - General Notes, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - START, 2002 August (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Conceptual Framework, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Draft Chapters to Secretariat, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Working Draft Glossary MA Conceptual Framework (2 copies), undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Logistics on Revised Chaps 2 and 8, 2003 Jan. 13 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Next MA Co-Chairs Call, 2002 Dec. 22 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Initial Drivers Participants List, 2002 Sept. 25 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - MA Next Steps, 2002 Dec. 22 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Thank You for Comments, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - MA Board Review Comments, 2003 Feb. 11 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Final Revisions to MA Conceptual Framework Chapt., 2003 Feb. 20 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - MA Secretariat - Activity Reports, 2003 Feb. 27 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - MA Secretariat Call on Feb. 27-Final, 2003 Feb. 25 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Managed Call Confirmation, 2003 Feb. 26 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Style Guide For Manuscript Preparation, 2002 Aug. 4 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Information Needed for Participation in December MA Meeting, 2002 Sept. 3 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Ecosystems and their Services, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Reviewers - Conceptual FW, 2002 Aug. 31 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - SDM-Draft, 2002 Sept. 10 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Revised SPM email, 2002 Aug. 28 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Ecosystems and People: A Framework for Assessment and Decision-Making Draft, 2002 Aug. 27 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Policy Makers Summary MA, 2002 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Reviewers_MA_General, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Virus, 2004 March 12 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Warning About E-Mail Account, 2004 March 3 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Crosscut MTG Freshwater Systems and Services, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Crosscut Plan: Health ( Health CC Planning Notes, Agenda, Invitations, Participants, Travel/Logistics, Well-being Meeting, Key Docs, Final Report), 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Drylands/ Desertification Cross-Cut Meeting (Photos, Teleconferences, Concepts + Paper, Planning, Presentations, Background Book, Agenda, Participants, Venue/Lodging, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Food Cross Cut, 2003 May (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Money Travel and Expenses, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Millennium Assessment, Dec. 2001 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - CLA Nominations KL, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - MA Secretariat Opens in Malaysia, 2002 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Millennium Assessment (KC Inductions), 2002 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Millennium Assessment Meeting Bilthoven, 2001 April (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2001 April (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2001 May (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2001 June (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2001 Aug. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2001 Oct. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Millennium Assessment-Design Workshop Capetown, 2001 Oct. 8-11 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2001 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Pilot Analysis of Global Ecosystems (Forests, Grasslands, Freshwater Systems), 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Consultant for Millennium Ecosystem Capacity Building Draft Terms of reference, 2002 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - MA Board Summary and Q&A's, 2002 Feb. 13 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Breakfast Note, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Kuala Lumpar Lodging, 2002 Jan. 8 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Flight Information, 2001 Nov. 29 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Malaysia - Assessment Panel Meeting Information, 2001 Oct. 18 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - MA Assessment Panel and Schedule Change + Document to Revi, 2001 Sept. 12 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Assessment Panel Meeting Response Form, 2002 Jan. 15-17 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Co-Chair Call Agenda and Background, 2002 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Millennium Ecosystem Assessment: Assessment Panel Meeting, 2002 Jan. 14- Jan. 17 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Millennium Ecosystem Assessment Board Meeting, 2002 Jan. 14-Jan. 16 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Microsoft Outlook, Build 10.0.2627, 2002 Jan. 26 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - MA Co-Chairs Call Agenda, 2002 Feb. 25 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Need for Follow-Up Phone Calls to CLAs, 2002 Feb. 17 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Millennium Assessment (Blank Folder), 2002 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - First Workshop of the Scenarios Working Group of the Millennium Assessment Port of Spain, Trinidad and Tobago, 2002 April 14-17 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2002 March (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Millennium Assessment Trinidad, 2002 April 17-21 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2002 May (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2002 April (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Millennium Assessment: 2nd meeting of the assessment panel, 2001 Jun 30-Jul 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2001 Jul (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Millennium Assessment, 2002 Jun (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Additional papers, Accession ARCH-2016-119
  - Livestock in a Living Landscape
    - CIAP, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Follow- up Contacts/ experts (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Environment watch (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Virtual workshop (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 81 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Livestock in a changing landscape (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Glossary - virtual, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Becky Chaplin/ Earth Sciences, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Virtual workshop 1 - final materials, 2004 Nov 15-17 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Positioning - Allocation, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Comments - memos VWS I summaries, 2004 Nov 15-17 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Virtual workshop I - CESP Final Summaries -WS 1, 2004 Nov 15-17 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Neville (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 81 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Misc. Livertock Landscape, 2006 Mar 26 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Review, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Stanford Initiative for the Environment grant, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - AAAS Washington DC, 2005 Feb 17-21 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Mooney folder (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Participant memos VWSII, 2005 Mar (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Virtual workshop II, 2005 Mar 8-10 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Ponc + Poultry Data project, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Agenda VWS II, 2005 Mar 8-10 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - VSW- I, 2004 Nov 4 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - LCL- Work Plan/Time line, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - LCL - Budget, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - LCL - Consultation Meeting Format, 2006 Nov (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - LCL - Author/Co-author lists, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - LCL - Steering Committee Contacts (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - LCL - General outline, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - LCL - Drivers Working group overall outline (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - LCL - Drivers working group Gerber - Livestock Geography, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - LCL - Drivers Working Group Pingali - underlying trends (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - LCL - Drivers Working Group de Hann - Structural change, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - LCL - drivers working group RAE - trends in consumption (Allen), 2005 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - LCL - Publication Development Methods (Scientific and technical volume) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - LCL - Publication development, methods drafts (case studies volume) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - LCL - Publication Development, Methods drafts (decision makers summary) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - LCL - publication development, methods drafts (businesss and industrysynthesis) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - LCL - Review Process/Review Editors (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - LCL - Teleconference Schedules Reports, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - LCL - Publisher Proposals/Prospectus (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - LCL - Drivers Working Group Summary (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - LCL - consequences working group Environment - ASNER - Archer Global Biogeochemical (carbon) (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - LCL - Consequences Working group summary (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - LCL - Consequences working group overall outline (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - LCL - Consequences working group environment - GALLOWAY Global biogeochemical (nitrogen), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - LCL - Consequences Working group environment - Deutsch-Folke Freshwater coastal, 2006 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - LCL - Consequences Working group environment - toutain-reid Terrestrial Extensive, 2006 Apr 21 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - LCL - Consequences Working group environment - Menzie Terrestrial intensive, 2006 Apr 15 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - LCL - Consequences Working Group Environment section summary (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - LCL - Consequences Working group health - Cahill Schlundt intensive focus, 2006 Apr (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - LCL - Consequences working group health - Bonfoh- Zinstag Extensive Focus, 2006 Apr 18 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - LCL - Consequences working group health - Neumann Nutrition Integrated View, 2006 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - LCL - Consequences working group health section summary (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - LCL - Consequences working group social - THU social issues intensive, 2006 Mar 28 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - LCL - Consequences working group social - Niamir Fuller Social issues extensive, 2006 May 22 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - LCL - Consequences working group social - OTTE (Joachim) Social issues integrated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - LCL - Consequences working group social section summary (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - LCL brochure drafts, 2006 Jun (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - LCL - Case studies working group overall outline (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - LCL - case studies working group general methodology plan (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - LCL - case studies working group summary (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - LCL - Responses working group general/overall outline (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - LCL - responses working group Kurup - smallholder issues (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - LCL - responses working group Cielslak - industry, Cargill (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - LCL - responses working group Noll - Johr - industry, Nestle (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - LCL - responses working group Mueller - Industry, DeGussa (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - LCL - Responses working group Steinfeld - Policy (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - LCL - Responses working group summary (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - LCL - case studies working group LY - Case Study West Africa (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - LCL - case studies working group Kjaer - Case study Europe (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - LCL - case studies working group Ke-Yutian- Case Study China (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - LCL - case studies working group Ibrahim - case study Latin America (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Ford Foundation, 2005 Jun (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Compton Foundation (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Columbia Foundation, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Vulcan, Inc/Paul G. Allen Family foundation (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation, 2005 Feb (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Sol Goldman Charitable Trust (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - UNEP - DGEF (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Sustainable Ag and food Systems Funders (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Park foundation, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Wallace Global Fund, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Clarence Heller Foundation, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Winslow Foundation, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Packard Foundation, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Rockefeller Bros Fund, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - World Bank, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Virtual edition, 2005 Aug (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Case Studies group VWS II, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Virtual workshop I invoices/receipts, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - CIAP - scope report, 2004 Mar 15 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - CIAP - scope report, 2005 Jan (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Scope report - CIAP, 2005 Oct (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - General (Fundraising) (Box 2, Folder 74)